[
    {
        "question": "If the bark and phloem tissue of a woody shoot are peeled off by ringing, the whole plant will eventually die because",
        "optionA": "water does not reach the leaves",
        "optionB": "water and salts remained below the ring portion",
        "optionC": "there is a withdrawal of water from the root by soil",
        "optionD": "manufactured food does not reach the roots",
        "answer": "manufactured food does not reach the roots"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following hormones is produced during fright or when agitated",
        "optionA": "Insulin",
        "optionB": "Thyroxine",
        "optionC": "Adrenalin",
        "optionD": "Pituitrin",
        "answer": "Adrenalin"
    },

    {
        "question": "Biconcave lenses are used in the correction of an eye defect called",
        "optionA": "myopia",
        "optionB": "colour blindnes",
        "optionC": "old age",
        "optionD": "hypermetropia",
        "answer": "myopia"
    },

    {
        "question": "The center which controls respiratory activities in the mammalian brain is the",
        "optionA": "medulla",
        "optionB": "cerebellum",
        "optionC": "pituitary organ",
        "optionD": "olfactory lobe",
        "answer": "medulla"
    },

    {
        "question": "A student trying to find out the order in which organisms appear on a cleared plot is studying one of the following",
        "optionA": "Ecosystem",
        "optionB": "Food chain",
        "optionC": "Food web",
        "optionD": "Succession",
        "answer": "Succession"
    },

    {
        "question": "An organism X lives entirely on the waste products in another organism Y. In this association X is a",
        "optionA": "symbionth",
        "optionB": "commensal",
        "optionC": "saprophyte",
        "optionD": "parasite",
        "answer": "commensal"
    },

    {
        "question": "During thunderstorms the energy of lightning discharge causes",
        "optionA": "oxygen and nitrogen to combine",
        "optionB": "more carbon dioxide to be formed",
        "optionC": "nitrites to be converted to nitrates",
        "optionD": "nitrates to be converted to nitrogen",
        "answer": "oxygen and nitrogen to combine"
    },

    {
        "question": "During excretion of urea there is also a corresponding re-absorption of water into the blood. This re-absorption takes place in the",
        "optionA": "uriniferous tubules",
        "optionB": "Bowman's capsule",
        "optionC": "glomerulus",
        "optionD": "malpighian capsule",
        "answer": "uriniferous tubules"
    },

    {
        "question": "In anaerobic respiration, glucose is converted to one of the following",
        "optionA": "Carbon dioxide and water",
        "optionB": "Carbon dioxide only",
        "optionC": "Carbon dioxide and alcohol",
        "optionD": "Alcohol and water",
        "answer": "Carbon dioxide and alcohol"
    },

    {
        "question": "The part of the cell solely responsible for respiration is the",
        "optionA": "nucleus",
        "optionB": "nucleolus",
        "optionC": "mitochondria",
        "optionD": "golgi apparatus",
        "answer": "mitochondria"
    },

    {
        "question": "A green plant growing in a compost pit is feeding",
        "optionA": "holozoically",
        "optionB": "parasitically",
        "optionC": "saprophytically",
        "optionD": " holophytically",
        "answer": " holophytically"
    },

    {
        "question": "A potometer is used to determine the rate at which a shoot",
        "optionA": "absorbs water",
        "optionB": "lost weight",
        "optionC": "transpires",
        "optionD": "sucks air bubbles",
        "answer": "ranspires"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which one of the following parts of the mammalian body is most closely associated with the production of urine?",
        "optionA": "Malpighian capsule",
        "optionB": "Ureter",
        "optionC": "Urethra",
        "optionD": "Urinary bladder",
        "answer": "Malpighian capsule"
    },

    {
        "question": "For pollination and fruit formation, the essential part(s) of the flower should be the",
        "optionA": "corolla",
        "optionB": "oovules",
        "optionC": "pistil (gynoecium)",
        "optionD": "ovary",
        "answer": "pistil (gynoecium)"
    },

    {
        "question": "The conversion of excess amino acids into urea occurs in the",
        "optionA": "kidney",
        "optionB": "liver",
        "optionC": "lungs",
        "optionD": "Small intestine",
        "answer": "liver"
    }
]